Aleksandr **Nevarko**

□ +7 925 203 27 42 | ■ aleksandr.nevarko@skoltech.ru | • AlexanderNevarko



Summary_

I am a 6-year student at MIPT and a 2-year student at Skoltech. I am keen on programming, physics, maths and mostly all other technical sciences. My main hobbies are cars and chess. I have an entrepreneurial spirit and a lot of will to create new interesting projects. I am looking forward to learning new areas of computer science and applications of physics and maths in it.

Experience

AURORAi Moscow, Russia

COMPUTER VISION ENGINEER

Mar 2022 - present

• Digit detection and classification on metal objects.

Samsung Al Center Moscow, Russia

RESEARCH INTERN

Jun 2021 - Jul 2021

- Personalized selfie editing project.
- Developed a conditional model.

Skoltech CV Lab Moscow, Russia

RESEARCHER Dec 2020 - present

 Asymmetric telepresence system via Microsoft Kinect and VR glasses. 3D Computer vision. Scientific director prof. Victor Lempitsky.

Huawei Moscow Russia

ENGINEER IN RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT

Nov 2020 - Feb 2021

• Data analysis digital signal processing in fiber optic communication systems.

Acronis Moscow, Russia

GOLANG INTERN IN RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT

Sep 2019 - Jul 2020

• Developing REST API Intelligent Fuzzing tester as a graduate work. The tool may become an opensource competitor for an analog from Microsoft Research RESTLer. Scientific director Anna Melekhova.

Laboratory for modeling and designing special computing architectures, MIPT

MIPT, Moscow, Russia

Jul 2019 - Oct 2020

PYTHON DEVELOPER / PHYSICIST

- Integrated a physical model of a ballistic rocket into the project.
- Developed a physical engine for phased antenna arrays.
- Improved a graphical phased antenna array geometry redactor.

Projects

PetSearch Moscow

WINNER OF LEADERS OF DIGITAL TRANSFORMATION 2021 HACKATON

Oct 2021

- A system, that lets users search for their lost dogs using data from CCTV cameras. It includes several components:
- Dogs detection in the CCTV camera images
- Dogs classification by color, tail length and breed
- · Finding out whether the dog has an owner nearby in the image
- Image information recognition (data, time, place)
- Wrapping everything up in a web-service

Energy of Breakthrough (https://github.com/maftukh/energy-hack)

Moscow

WINNER

Oct 2021

- Control system for gas distribution network of a city
- · Predicting optimal parameters for gas valves with restrictions for best gas distribution of the network

BCG GAMMA Hackathon on Digital Healthcare

(https://github.com/AlexanderNevarko/bcg-hack)

PARTICIPANT Jul 2021

· Analysis of SARS and flu incidence rate data.

• Search for factors that affect the non-epidemiological incidence rate in different cities of Russia.

MICCAI AutoImplant 2021 Challenge

(https://github.com/aniton/AutoImplant-2020-2021)

Skoltech

Moscow

PARTICIPANT May 2021 • Problem: automatic cranial implant design. Create a solution, that given a skull with a defect, generates a 3D model of a

- cranial implant specifically for the patient.
- 3 approaches tried: baseline from authors, winning solution from 2020 challenge, 2020 SOTA 2D segmentation network (SAUNet) applied for 3D.
- SAUNet showed the best result.

Emotion tracker

(https://github.com/AlexanderNevarko/emotion-tracker)

Skoltech

ML ENGINEER Dec 2020 A system for real-time emotion tracking using web-camera. Useful to collect better feedback from online lectures and sem-

- inars.
- Dataset collection and analysis.
- Different approaches from classical CV to neural networks and Facebook ready-to-run pre-trained networks tested for speed and accuracy.
- Implementation for laptop web-camera usage.

Public places access system (frtk.mipt.ru / 8ka.mipt.ru)

MIPT

2020 - 2022

PROJECT LEAD

2017-2018 • Website with online timetable for some shared recourses in dormitories. Implemented for washing machine rooms.

- Booking and paying possibility on the site.
- Hardware electronic locker for key-card access to washing machine room.
- Developed by a team of 4 members, sold to 2 dormitories in MIPT.
- Won RedBull Basement University 2018 in Russia with that project.

Education

Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology

INSTITUTE FOR INFORMATION TRANSMISSION PROBLEMS

Dolgoprudny, Russia DEPARTMENT OF RADIO ELECTRONICS AND CYBERNETICS 2016 - 2022

SUB-DEPARTMENT OF THEORETICAL AND APPLIED INFORMATICS, AFFILIATED WITH ACRONIS 2018 - 2020

Skoltech Skolkovo, Russia

DEPARTMENT OF DATA SCIENCE 2020 - 2022

Skills_

Languges English (upper intermediate), German (B1)

Programming Python, Go, C/C++, git, Linux

Maths Linear algebra, mathematical analysis, differential equations, probability theory, etc.

Physics General physics, quantum mechanics **Soft Skills** Leadership, communications, teamwork

Honors & Awards.

Winner of the Russian stage, Red Bull Basement University

Final Stage Winner, Russian National Physics School Olympiad

Moscow / Berlin Sochi, Russia

ALEKSANDR NEVARKO · RÉSUMÉ